Jean-Baptiste TRAHIN

Los Angeles, CA · (424) 625-8403 · jb.trahin@gmail.com

Consumer web product manager with 2 years' experience. Worked as a business developer before transitioning to product management. Recently moved to the Los Angeles area after obtaining a green card.

Employment

Denormalise – *Product Manager*

San Francisco – 11/2013 to 05/2015

Denormalise is a website that offers adventure travels to seekers of life-changing experiences.

- · Managed product team of two engineers and implemented product roadmaps using Agile methodologies
- Led project to redesign website using a data-driven approach, which resulted in a 95% increase in monthly unique visitors
- Achieved a 25% increase in conversion rate by rethinking the customer onboarding experience and developing personalization features
- Led the design of new social media features to grow product adoption and showed a 50% increase in newsletter signups
- Initiated the built of a new user checkout experience to reduce customer drop-off

The French Tech Hub – Business Development Representative

San Francisco – 12/2011 to 11/2013

The French Tech Hub is a growth accelerator that helps French technology companies with international expansion.

- Developed new sales process to qualify, engage and close new startup level business opportunities using Salesforce
- Increased the number of business leads in database by 600%, leading to a 150% total revenue growth
- · Conducted lead follow-up, retention calls and service calls through telemarketing and one-on-one meetings
- Built and implemented over 50 targeted emailing campaigns to strengthen the consistency of marketing actions and messages

Franklin Templeton Investments – Sales & Marketing Support

Paris – 10/2010 to 11/2011

- Collaborated with Sales & Marketing executives to increase adoption of firm's investment products among institutional clients
- Populated industry databases and company's training tools (Franklin Templeton Academy) with up-to-date inflation and net asset value numbers, volatility and asset class diversification tutorials

Select Skillsets & Proficiencies

- Languages: Native French, Fluent English and Basic German
- Knowledge of HTML5, CSS3 & Javascript; experience with Twitter Bootstrap & Jquery
- PM tools : Slack, Trello, Evernote, Balsamiq
- CRM & Analysis tools: Salesforce, Crowdfire, Hootsuite & Tweetdeck, Mailchimp
- Microsoft Office Proficient and Excel Power User

Education Simplon.co

Web Developer 6 months online intensive program

Currently enrolled

ESAM (European School of Advanced Management), Paris

Master's Degree in Finance

2011

2009

ESAM (European School of Advanced Management), Paris

Bachelor's Degree in Business Administration

Spring Semester 2009

San Francisco State University; College of Business

Study Abroad Exchange Program